,id,type,date,text,named_entities
0,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t525546_article_23,article,1920-10-04,"(By Special Cable to the Herald.)
Cnicaco, Sunday.—The Chicago
Health Commissioners declare
that whererer death results
through. tlie refusal of landlords
to provide sufficient heat, they
will be brought to trial von a
charge of murder. During. the
severe epidemic of influenza last
gear and therprevious gear, many
cases merealleged-to have been
due directlg to the insufficiener of
the heat suppty in apartmeuts","[('Special Cable', 'ORG'), ('Herald', 'LOC'), ('Cnicaco', 'GPE'), ('Chicago', 'GPE'), ('Health Commissioners', 'ORG')]"
1,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t525546_article_192,article,1920-10-04,"phlegm,'' she says.No Ameriran audience,
with all its väunted pep, everrose to a baited
line thieway-ther did for the- lines here. The
answer, I think, is the pit. Treally#think it's
a shame we can't have it in New Vork.
Every London theatre lias at the rear. of
the orchestra stalls from six#to twenty rows
of benches. Admission to them is, roughly,
fifty cents and no seats are reserved. For a
successful production long lines of men and
Women,, wait inthe rain for hours to get good
places in these rush seats. It ditfers from
the American. “gallery'' in that it brings
this body of unsophisticated susceptibility, if
Fouschoose toscall it that—whafever it is, it's
susceptibleirand enthusiastic—right into lhe
main body of the. house. It’seright back of
the coldlz critical three-dollar stalls and
eilher in approval or disapproval it makes
the atmosphere in which the play is received.
Pit and Critics.
So powerful is this influence that during
the epidemies of influenza
the London
theatrical managers successfully resisted appeals by. the health authorities to do away
with the pit qucues. The learned theatrical
critics, of the“Times' or ihe“Morning
Post’' mnay be utterly bored by a production
—yet if it meets the approval of the pittiter
it is asuccess—and there have been a halfdozen of these successes within the last few
seasons towards which the critics have been
compelled eventuallyto change their opinions
and to admit that the pit was right.
Miss Nash heatedly denied just before sailing that there was ever the slightest expression of dislike for American actresses or
actors on the grounds of their nationalit","[('Ameriran', 'PERSON'), ('New Vork', 'GPE'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('fifty cents', 'MONEY'), ('hours', 'TIME'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('three-dollar', 'MONEY'), ('Pit and Critics', 'ORG'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Nash', 'PERSON'), ('American', 'NORP')]"
2,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52949f_article_168,article,1919-11-03,"Fesigus are already erident that an
influenza cpidemie mav be expected,
said an eminent Paris physician gesterday. It is cxpccted that the cpidemic, which is not of a dangerous nature, as was that of last autumn, will
manifest itself with the ordinar
symptoms of a cold and sick-headache
ghich if neglected devclops and crcates
a farorable ground fertile for the in
fluenza germ. But the cases recorded
this Fear are more like che old-fash
ioned influcnza, which lasts from ührce
days to a fortnight, It can be treated
rapidlg by going directly to bed, eren
if onlg for twenty-four hours by eating
light but extremely nourishing food
and by keeping oneself in good Spirits
This infuenza need not be viewed
with alarm. No pncumonia is present,
except-in veiy exceptional cases.","[('Paris', 'GPE'), ('last autumn', 'DATE'), ('days', 'DATE'), ('twenty-four hours', 'TIME'), ('pncumonia', 'GPE')]"
3,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52466v_article_4,article,1920-07-08,"For some days rumor has been busy- concerning a spirit ol revolt which has been
manifested among civil forces of lhe Crown
in at least IWo counties. In öne centre,affecting a considerable aren, it is statedi that
fourteen resignations were sent in simultaneously. Two officers of high rank, military
and civil, hurried to the scene to make an
investigation as to the cause of- the trouble.
They found the situation even worse than
they had expecteg, and negotiations carried
on with the spokesmen orer sandbag: defences failed to establish a disciplinary Spirit.
This epidemic of resignations is spreading.
The men refuse to temporise with any armed
forces, and they will fraternise with none
butcivilian townsfolk, between whom and
thiemselves there had been previouslyrgrowing
a dangerous antagonism.
The military authorities: in Lotidondert
have prohibited the Orange ccicbratien oflthe
anniversary, of the. Battlerof, the Boyne - on
take
Manday next, which was. orgänised to
placelat Glendermöt.
In County Wexiord ihe Irish- Republican
Army häs takenaver lhic powers of. the licensing, authorities, and.ndtices. hare been handerl
to proprietors, of. salons, informing theni that
hy a ruling of the“Republican courts'' their
premises are.to be open only between'tlic
hours of 8 alm, and 9 p.m., and no drink
may be sold on Sundays or Cliurch holidays","[('some days', 'DATE'), ('Crown', 'PRODUCT'), ('fourteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Spirit', 'ORG'), ('Lotidondert', 'GPE'), ('Orange', 'NORP'), ('Battlerof', 'PERSON'), ('Boyne', 'PERSON'), ('Manday', 'DATE'), ('Glendermöt', 'PERSON'), ('County Wexiord', 'FAC'), ('Republican', 'NORP'), ('Army', 'ORG'), ('theni', 'PRODUCT'), (""only between'tlic\nhours"", 'TIME'), ('8', 'CARDINAL'), ('9 p.m.', 'TIME'), ('Sundays', 'DATE')]"
4,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51517t_article_43,article,1919-06-06,"Sir Boverton Redwood, the petroleum
expert, died suddenly in London on
Wednesday in his seventy-fourth year.
Sir Boverton held many appointments
under Government and public bodies
and wrôte many books on petroleum.
Eight American Red Cross nurses were
yesterday decorated in Athens by King
Alexander of Greece with the Medal of
Military Merit for their work in fighting the typhus epidemic in Mecedonia
They were: Miss Sara Addison, Baltimore; Miss Marie Glauber, Chicago;
Miss Alma Hartz, Davenport, Ia.; Miss
Isabelle Martin, San Francisco; Miss
Emily Porter, Bridgeport, Conn.; Miss
Clarissa Blakeslee, Drexel Hill, Pa.;
Miss Edith Gienn, Bristol, Pa.; Miss
Florence Stone, Plainfield, N.J. In
making the presentation, King Alexander spoke feelingly of his gratitude to
America. After the ceremony the American Minister presented to the King
two of the members of the Red Cross.
mission, Major Burke C. Hamilton, of
Goshen, N.F., and Major Robert Bruce
Wallace, of Oleveland.","[('Boverton Redwood', 'PERSON'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('seventy-fourth year', 'DATE'), ('Boverton', 'PERSON'), ('Government', 'ORG'), ('Eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('American Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('Athens', 'GPE'), ('Greece', 'GPE'), ('Mecedonia', 'GPE'), ('Sara Addison', 'PERSON'), ('Baltimore', 'GPE'), ('Marie Glauber', 'PERSON'), ('Chicago', 'GPE'), ('Alma Hartz', 'PERSON'), ('Davenport', 'GPE'), ('Ia.', 'GPE'), ('Isabelle Martin', 'PERSON'), ('San Francisco', 'GPE'), ('Miss', 'PERSON'), ('Emily Porter', 'PERSON'), ('Bridgeport', 'GPE'), ('Conn.', 'GPE'), ('Clarissa Blakeslee', 'PERSON'), ('Drexel Hill', 'ORG'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Edith Gienn', 'PERSON'), ('Bristol', 'GPE'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Florence Stone', 'PERSON'), ('Plainfield', 'GPE'), ('N.J.', 'GPE'), ('King Alexander', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('Burke C. Hamilton', 'PERSON'), ('Goshen', 'GPE'), ('N.F.', 'GPE'), ('Robert Bruce', 'PERSON'), ('Wallace', 'PERSON'), ('Oleveland', 'ORG')]"
5,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54033j_article_261,article,1920-05-13,"M. Léon Bernard at the last sitting ol
the Kcadémie de Médecine gave some details
olthe proposal of the Ministry 6f Hygiene
to establish an Institute of Hygiene in Paris
at an early date.
The institute will undertake the study of
all questions relating to alimentary hygiene
and hygienic conditions of labor, in addition
to epidemic diseases. It will constitute a
school of public heallh and will train medical
specialists.","[('M. Léon Bernard', 'PERSON'), ('Kcadémie de Médecine', 'PERSON'), ('an Institute of Hygiene', 'ORG'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('an early date', 'DATE')]"
6,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54016x_article_284,article,1920-04-25,"Paris has“plaiditis' as far as
fashions are concerned, and tliere seems
to. be absolutely no cure-for it. In a
milder form it might be called “stripitis.“ Women have been checkered
and striped for the last two years, and
still the. fabric makers say that more
of such designs are to come with thc
autumn. Thei epidemic is apparently
not pechliar to Paris alone, for Neu
Vork seems to have had the disease in
a more violent form, and will, therefore, be the first to recover
While the French weavers decided to
perfect, the plaids and stripes by inaking them appear einbroidered and
beaded on the fabric. the American
manufacturers turned threm ont in such
millions that they hare grown common.
The result will be that American women, wlio have been prevented from
coming'to France for the. last'six Fears
to choose their own dresses, will become
ill at the sight of anything that locks
like checks or'stripes, as they have only
recently gotrid of the Splaiditis“
germ.
The Scotch plaids came in with a
whoop about two Fears ago, after the
little Parisienne had been hobnobbing
with the Highlanders und decided
she. liked their kilts, so it will
not be surprising if “plaiditis'
stays, with us in this part of
the world for yet another year. The
Scotch featüre“ of the plaids, however,
seeins to have worn off to some extent,
and they have become daring designs
in tremendous squares. The five-inch
squares, even in any Combination so
striking as black and white, seem tame
now. Capes and coats and' even whole
tailored costumes are made of checkered fabrics. with the checks measuring
a foot'square. In fact, the checksare
so liuge in the newest. materials#that
some of the mantles have somcthing of
a lialf-and-half effect, with one square
of one color displayed in front, while
thie next square of a contrasting color
covers the back, suggesting“gol' and
'stop’' street-sign. effect
The fact that plaids have groun so
huge in their design might be responsible for tlie pleated skirts that have
gröwn'so modish, for the-dressmakers
have evidently decided that the only
way to hold the checks within bounds
is to pleat them, thus making them
about oner half their original size.
One of the smartest costumes at the
faces a few days ago had a bläck and","[('Paris', 'GPE'), ('the last two years', 'DATE'), ('thc\nautumn', 'PERSON'), ('Thei', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Neu\nVork', 'ORG'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('millions', 'CARDINAL'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), (""or'stripes"", 'GPE'), ('Splaiditis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Scotch', 'NORP'), ('two Fears ago', 'DATE'), ('Parisienne', 'PRODUCT'), ('Highlanders', 'NORP'), ('another year', 'DATE'), ('Scotch', 'NORP'), ('five-inch', 'QUANTITY'), ('Combination', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('half', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('a few days ago', 'DATE')]"
7,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52907q_article_73,article,1919-09-22,"Some Deaths Are Reported, but
Epidemic.
Lornos, Sunday.—ho returns ol
the Registrar-General show that nine
deaths froin influenza occurred in London last weck, and that in tlio 96
greut towns of Ensland and Wales the
number of deaths was 29.
Tho average of deaths in London is
returned as 5. In che other towns tho
numbers weckly have ranged from 33
the first quarter of the year, when the
cpidemic was raging in this country,
influenza was either a primary or a
contributory causé of death in. 10
fewer than 37,697 casos.
Thore are no signs of a return of
the influenza opidemie,? declares an
oflicial of the Ministry of Health.","[('Lornos', 'PERSON'), ('Registrar', 'ORG'), ('nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ensland', 'GPE'), ('Wales', 'GPE'), ('29', 'DATE'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('5', 'CARDINAL'), ('33', 'CARDINAL'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('the current quarter', 'DATE'), ('the first quarter of the year', 'DATE'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('fewer than 37,697', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Ministry of Health', 'ORG')]"
8,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539237_article_6,article,1920-01-23,"Cutcado, Thursday.—wo thousand
unch eight new eases of influenza and
181 nei easecs of pneumoniaaro rcported to-duy. Hitherto influenza has
been responsible for 6I deaths and
pneunionja for 21
Arsärr, Thursday.—Mr. Smith, Governor of. Now „Tork State, gave a
luncheon yesterday to De Valera, uho
is here to hegin his campaign Tor ehe
sale öf Trish bonds., Mr. Watt, the
Mayor of Albany, gave a reception in
honor-of. De Valern in the cvening","[('Cutcado', 'GPE'), ('thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('181', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hitherto influenza', 'PERSON'), ('21', 'CARDINAL'), ('Arsärr', 'ORG'), ('Smith', 'GPE'), ('Tork State', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('De Valera', 'ORG'), ('Trish', 'NORP'), ('Watt', 'PERSON'), ('Albany', 'GPE'), ('De Valern', 'PERSON')]"
9,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539237_article_81,article,1920-01-23,"One day Harrington twisted a
button olf his conb. Hie hated to sew.
So he hunted threngh the little villago
until he found a motherlz' woman,
whom he asked to repair his coat.
Tho woman was Umé. Frèrejacque.
While the repair work was under way
Mme. Frèrejacque's daughter, Angole
Frèrejacque, came in
Thab settlerl it for Jack Harrington;
also for Angele. Neither could speak
the language of thc other. But thab
was not necessary. Each knew tho
universal language of lore. In time
he was inrited to the Frérejacque
hiome for Sunday dinner. Other dinner
juritations followed.
Harrington was taken ill with influenza. Men were dring like flies of
the epidemic. He secured leare of
absence and went to the Frèrejacque
home. They nursed him back to health.
*I would have died had I remained
in the hospital,' Harrington say's.
Harrington and Angele Frerejacque
were married March 20, 1918, in Marey-sur-Tille. The entire toyn attended the wedding.
in France, Harrington was ordered
back to America. He ahd-his little
bride sailed in the Mercurg.: The
Mercurg docked at Newport News
on July 5. Threo dags later Jack Harrington was given his discharge and
started for Lincoln with his wife. His
old position with the Burlington rail¬","[('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Harrington', 'GPE'), ('Mme', 'PERSON'), ('Frèrejacque', 'ORG'), ('Angole\nFrèrejacque', 'PRODUCT'), ('Thab', 'GPE'), ('Jack Harrington', 'PERSON'), ('Angele', 'PERSON'), ('Frérejacque', 'NORP'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Harrington', 'GPE'), ('Frèrejacque', 'ORG'), ('Harrington', 'GPE'), ('Angele Frerejacque', 'PERSON'), ('March 20, 1918', 'DATE'), ('Marey', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Harrington', 'GPE'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('Mercurg', 'GPE'), ('Mercurg', 'PERSON'), ('Newport News', 'FAC'), ('July 5', 'DATE'), ('Jack Harrington', 'PERSON'), ('Lincoln', 'ORG'), ('Burlington', 'ORG'), ('rail¬', 'GPE')]"
10,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53302x_article_212,article,1918-11-09,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
Lowpox, Friday.—The epidemie of
influenza, though it is still serious, is
undoubtedly decreasing. Police, omnibus employés and nurses are gradually
returning toduty. One of the latest
victims is Captain B. C. Hücks, the
well-known aviator, who was the first
to loop tle Joop. in England. He died.
of double pneumoniz.","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('B. C. Hücks', 'PERSON'), ('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('Joop', 'LOC'), ('England', 'GPE')]"
11,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51366d_article_84,article,1919-01-05,"Mr. Douglas Littleton, one er che most
popatar Attachés of the American Embassy, died on Fridayafter a# chort.IIl.
usss, Tvo weeke ago Nr. Littleion
eaught influenza, which develobsd inte
pncumenis, He was taken to Dr. Blake'g
hospital, where he received every attention, but where, owing toa weak heart,
all efforts to. save kit lite proved unavailing.
Nr. Littleton came to Parise few
months ago and quickly made many
friends here. Herwas in charge of diplomatic passgorts at#the Embasey. Herwag
nincteen yeors of age and oneof#thé
Foungstt onthe Embatsy. steff. Bis
father is ex-Congressman Martin Little
ion, a leader atthe Bar of Kings
Coünty, New Vork, and in the. State
Demecratio partg. Funeral arrangemente have not béen made pending word
from Ameries.","[('Douglas Littleton', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Attachés', 'PERSON'), ('the American Embassy', 'ORG'), ('Fridayafter', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tvo', 'PERSON'), (""Blake'g\nhospital"", 'PERSON'), ('kit lite', 'PERSON'), ('Littleton', 'PERSON'), ('Parise few\nmonths ago', 'DATE'), ('nincteen', 'DATE'), ('Foungstt onthe Embatsy', 'ORG'), ('Martin Little', 'PERSON'), ('New Vork', 'GPE'), ('Demecratio', 'PERSON'), ('Ameries', 'ORG')]"
12,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53928s_article_40,article,1920-01-28,"(BT SPECIAL, CABIE TO THE HER.T.D.)
NEw Tonk, Tucsday.—The fact that
there hare been only 1,712 new cases
of influenza reported during the past
twenty-four hours does not gire any
satisfaction to the liealth authorities,
for they claim that physicians have
nôt reported during Saturday and Sunday. These reports will be reccived at
the Board of Health to-day and will
gire a big jump to tho total of cases
during the next twenty-four hours.
Dr. Copeland states that the disease
this gear is of a much milder form than
that which swept the country last gear.
as is eridenced by the fewer number
of deatlis. Howerer, the epidemic is
sweeping the countrg from the Atlantic to the Pacific, haring appeared in
California during the past forty-eight
hours, and being prevalent now in
twenty-one States.
The iliness of screral atfendants in
the magistrates' courts has halted mauy
legal proceedings. Sis kecpers and
fiftz'-one prisoners hare been removed
from the Tombs to Belleruc as victims
of the epidemic.
Haif a million dollars has been appropriated. br Congress for rescarch
work in combating influenza through
the Püblie Heaith serricc.","[('BT SPECIAL', 'ORG'), ('only 1,712', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-four hours', 'TIME'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('the Board of Health', 'ORG'), ('twenty-four hours', 'TIME'), ('Copeland', 'PERSON'), ('last gear', 'DATE'), ('Atlantic', 'LOC'), ('Pacific', 'LOC'), ('California', 'GPE'), ('the past forty-eight\nhours', 'DATE'), ('twenty-one', 'CARDINAL'), ('States', 'GPE'), (""fiftz'-one"", 'CARDINAL'), ('Tombs', 'ORG'), ('Haif a million dollars', 'ORG'), ('Congress', 'ORG'), ('Püblie Heaith', 'ORG')]"
13,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53214k_article_194,article,1918-08-13,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
A Ponr i FaANon, Saturday.—Here
in this port, never beforer written about
in the HEnärn since the war, so far as
hospitals are çoncerned, the situation is
one of remarkable organization.
Here, in this district, — this town
anda town near(by —, there is hospital
accommodation for about 26,000 patients.
Base. Hospital No. 38 represents the
Philadelphia Jefferson unit, and the
medigal staff is under Colonel J. S.
Lambie of Jefferson Medical School.
There are over#thirty döctors in this
hospital, anditheir services are distributed among 300 patients, which means
that this contingent gets mighty. good
care. However, thereris room for 3,000
patients, while in times of pressure
3,000 more can be accommodated, Added
to this there#is a conyalescent camp
for.2,000 men, which brings up the total
to 8,000.
In the same town is Base Hospital
No: 34; gver which Colonel Devoe presides. The colonel is from the University
of Pennsylvania. This hospital resemblee
theiAAmerican: Hospital at Neuilly, inasmuch asitrisa new seminary taken over
for sther AAmerican, wolinded. Everything
hereuis:spickand, span. It was opened
in January, Butrpätients did not como
until threermonths afterward. The colonelsthinks. it more suitable for hospital
purposes than most places taken over for
therarmg. He says#the entire building,
withrannexes, is wonderfully well ärranged, and-süch details as the sewage
arenofthe best modern arrangements.
There is accommodation hère for 1,300
patients. Most öf the medical staff of
eighteen doctors come from- Philadelphia; being connected with the Episcopal. Haspital there. It is ageneral hospital and not liinited to special cases.
Kind French-Townfolk.
The cölonel issenthusiastic about the
waykind-hearted people of the town help
in every way-possible to distract the
woundedmen. They organize concerts
and get artists from Paris. The patients
sit out under the trees and listen to che
music, thoroughly enjoy themselves, and
they are very appreciative of the efforts
maderhy thie French people. Colonel
Devoeisays:The feeling here between
ourfarmy men and the townspeople is
veryfiné. The inhahitants are perfectly
delightful and helpeus in many ways.
I asked him if he had anytrouble
withithe influenza wave.es, indeed,
was the reply.We had 100of our personneldown with it. Happily there
were no complications, and in ihree or
fonr days we were: all wellagain. Tlie
flu'#isan awkward thing to combat in
a höspital when it attacks the doctors
and nurses. It was. lucky, that we got
off. so easy.
At a place near here is another hospital, getting into, shape. It. will accommodate from 12,000 to 15,000 patients.
Thensthere is another enormous hospital
in anradjoining town where patients are
réceived frem'the ürst-mentioned hospitals. If theso wöundedimnen are found
tobe incurable er if theichances are that,
they will not be of use ät the front again,
tliéy aré.sent back home to America
It’will be seen that thel enormous hopital.accömmodation for American trootps
in France is very ingenious. As wounlledmen come from the front they mhy
pass. through quite a number of hospitals, Thov go gradually from the front
toward one of the hospital ports, where
ther accommodation is very great. The
nearer they get-to the sen the beiter
theyarerlikely to. become, so that they
von arerable to return to the front
ägain, or, iftheyshow no prospert of
Güicktrecovery; theyfare sent, back hhme.
Askedwhat was the Drincipal iliness
that bur men were subject to in this distriet, a medicalofficer told me:The
Americans—at any rate, those whom I
have had to deal with—are subfect to
bronchial affections in this climate.“","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Ponr', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('anda town', 'ORG'), ('near(by', 'GPE'), ('about 26,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('38', 'CARDINAL'), ('Philadelphia Jefferson', 'ORG'), ('J. S.\nLambie', 'PERSON'), ('Jefferson Medical School', 'ORG'), ('300', 'CARDINAL'), ('3,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('3,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('8,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Base Hospital', 'FAC'), ('34', 'CARDINAL'), ('Devoe', 'PERSON'), ('University', 'ORG'), ('Pennsylvania', 'GPE'), ('theiAAmerican:', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('AAmerican', 'NORP'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('1,300', 'CARDINAL'), ('eighteen', 'CARDINAL'), ('Philadelphia', 'GPE'), ('Episcopal', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('French', 'NORP'), (""Tlie\nflu'#isan"", 'PERSON'), ('12,000 to 15,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('mhy', 'ORG'), ('Drincipal', 'PERSON'), ('bur', 'ORG'), ('Americans', 'NORP')]"
14,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52869r_article_3,article,1919-08-15,"NovonostsK, Russia (hy courier to
Constantinople).—An epidemic of Asiatie choiera is raging in this city. The
deäth-räte äverages 120 a day. Sixtz
fire per cent. of the cases prove fatalPhysiciaus of the American Red
Cross are treating the crews of foreign
ships with-anti-cholera serum and have
furnished serum“ for use by the health
authorities of the city","[('Russia', 'GPE'), ('120', 'CARDINAL'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Red\nCross', 'ORG')]"
15,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t531848_article_8,article,1918-07-14,"ing
ack
in
ards
ack
ing
ards
10
tion
11
ack
ge,
lass
Dising
ing
cue
aly
isk
un
O
uE
il
lier
eat
ter,
ion
12
M. CLENENCEAU, PREMIER
(Special Telegram to the“Herald.))
Dy DON HARIM.
WITH THE AMERIGAN ARMIEs,
Saturday.
General Pershing has sent to M.
Clemenceau the following telegram:—
On this Fourteenth of July, a
day so symbolic of the will and determination of France, I desire. to
renew my expression of admiration
for the splendid courage of her
people and the gallantry of her
soldiers. We, of the American Expeditionary Forces, find in her
spirit a constant source of inspiration and encouragement.
Wherever the Allied flags flu the
French National. Fete will be celebrated
to-dau—in France, in England, in the
United States, in South America. and in
the island, possessions of the. Allies.
The chiej event in Paris scill be the
reviem oj troops at nine o'clock this
morning in the Bois de Boulogne. The
jull programme of the dag is gieen below.","[('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('11', 'CARDINAL'), ('ge', 'ORG'), ('un', 'ORG'), ('12', 'CARDINAL'), ('Saturday', 'DATE'), ('General Pershing', 'ORG'), ('M.\nClemenceau', 'PERSON'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('the American Expeditionary Forces', 'ORG'), ('Allied', 'ORG'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('United States', 'GPE'), ('South America', 'LOC'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), (""nine o'clock"", 'TIME'), ('the Bois de Boulogne', 'FAC'), ('dag', 'ORG')]"
16,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t532747_article_53,article,1918-10-12,"monia. In a certain number of cases
oven tbe symptoms of pleurisy hare been
observed, with a tendency to purulency.
In the present cpidemic some cases of
tho intestinal form of the malady have
beon observed, but the most numerous
assume tho pulmonary form. When the
Bulmonary congestion is very intense,
the victims become cyanosed and even
assumo a blackish huc. This has, incorrectly, spread the ides among tho public
that tho real cause of the discoloration
is cholera
The general prognosis of the ordinary
form of influenza is very benign. The
grovity resides in the complications.
During the 1889-90 epidemié about 5,500
persons succumbed to infiuenza in Paris,
and there were pulmonary complications in most cäses. Last week 192
dleaths were recorded, that
mortality
being lower than the mortality of 1889.
At the same time 400 cases of influenza
were reported daily, as compared with
1,000 in 1889, when twosthirds of the
Parisian population were affected. The
cmission of a large quantity of urine
and the appearance of abundant perspiration generally foreshadow the end
of the iliness.","[('1889-90', 'DATE'), ('about 5,500', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Last week', 'DATE'), ('192', 'CARDINAL'), ('1889', 'DATE'), ('400', 'CARDINAL'), ('daily', 'DATE'), ('1,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('1889', 'DATE'), ('Parisian', 'NORP')]"
17,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t532747_article_54,article,1918-10-12,"Directly che first symptoms of influenza appehr the sufferer must keep the
bed, for it has been noticed that the
complicated forms occur especially in
persons who hare zaken a chill during
the progression of their malady. Quinine must be taken in small doses (two
Gachets of 30 ceutigrammes during the
day), a low dietary must bei followed
and hot drinks must be taken abundantly. An excellent plan is to provoke
sudation with 30 centigrammes öf pyramidon, followed ten minutes later br
60 centigrammes of bi-chlorhydrate o
quinine. In cases where asthenia predominates Eypodermie injections of
campliorated eil are (prescribed; sor
gastro-intestinal forms mild purgations
with sulphate of soda or sulphate of
inagnesia","[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('the\nday', 'DATE'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten minutes later', 'TIME'), ('br\n', 'PERSON'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('Eypodermie', 'PERSON')]"
18,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t532747_article_55,article,1918-10-12,"For the thoracic forms the treatment comprises subcutaneous injections of colloidal silver; seven hours
after the injection 30 centigrammes of
pyramidon are administered, and ten
minutes subsequently 60 centigrammes
of bi-chlorhydrate of quinine; in the
cvening a cachet containing 40 centigrammes of Dover's powder is administered.
There remains the great question of
prophylagy. The essential points are ta
groid coming in contact with sufferers
From influenza, to. inject gomenolized
oil into the nostrils, to cleanse the moutl
and tecth frequently and to gargle three
or sour times deily with boracic water.
I6 is nccessary, furthermore, to avoid
all agglomerations of human beings, not
1o go tö theutres er 1o cinema halls, to
air the dwnlling ranms, to take great
precautions as ie, personal cleanliness
and to vaporize tha bedrooms with
water perfumed with bonzoin or encalgtus. There is no nced. tö change anything in oue's ordinary regimen
Tüc. Academy of Medicine has been
asked by tlie French Goverument to deal
with the question of individual measures
to be taken to combat the epidemic. The
committee appointed by the Academy of
Medicine will present its report on Tuesday, and on Wednesday the readers of
the Hrnarp-will be informed of its findings.","[('seven hours', 'TIME'), ('30', 'CARDINAL'), ('ten\nminutes', 'TIME'), ('60', 'CARDINAL'), ('40', 'CARDINAL'), ('Dover', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('I6', 'PRODUCT'), ('1o', 'CARDINAL'), ('1o', 'CARDINAL'), ('oue', 'ORG'), ('Tüc', 'ORG'), ('Academy of Medicine', 'ORG'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('the Academy of\nMedicine', 'ORG'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Hrnarp', 'ORG')]"
19,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t532747_article_58,article,1918-10-12,"Influenza is not, as had hoen said, a
new disesse. It appeared in Europe at
the commencement of the fifteenth century, andl wo have records of scveral
hundreds öf epidlemies since that epoch:
In France the most important were those
of 1803, 1833, 1837 and that of 1889.
All tliese epidemies presented practically
ibe same charscteristies. Inlluenza, or
grippe, is an infectioug disease, but
ther exach identity of the mierobe which
produces it has not yet bcen established.
Some authorities ahtribute is to tho
Pfeiffer cocco-bacillus, others to the
streptococcus; recently the spirecheeta
has been incriminated,
Very probably it is due to neither of
them, but to a specifie mierobe which
passes. through the densest filters and is
Invisible under the microscope. The
lther microbes mentioned may merely
interveue 1o create complicatichs.
Generally, infiuenza starts suddenly
with shivering, painful fehrile lassitude
uind violent headache; the feverishness
rises rapidly to a high degree, which may
aitain 40.ödeg. Cent. Sometimes this
fever is accompanied by delirium. When
the malady is definitely manifested the
same symptoms occur with invariable
reddening of the skin, the headache increases, the patients dread noise and
light; all their muscular masses become
painful; their tongues are covered with
an opaline slime, their thirst is quenchless and their appetite nil.
In somo instances bleeding from the
nose is observed. Almost always the
urine contains albumine, but in a modcrate qusntity. The spleen often increnses in volume.
The. illness lasts from four to eight
days. Its decline is progressive and is
generally preceded by profuse perspiration, sometimes also by dangerous diarrheea or of the appearence of herpes on
ihe lips. The period of convaiescence
may be very lengthy. Even in so-called
simple forms of influenza the patients
remain a relatively long time in a condition of asthenia, or debility, characterized by intellectual, moral and physical
weakness.
Of tho various forms of the malady,
the most common is that described abore.
The uervous form may causs troubles in
the membranes of the brain or of the
spinal cord; the gastro-intestinal form
may be accompanied by complications of
a. dysenteric natifre; the gravest of all
is the thoracic form, which causes either
scute bronchitis or else broncho-pncu¬","[('Influenza', 'NORP'), ('Europe', 'LOC'), ('the fifteenth century', 'DATE'), ('hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('1803, 1833,', 'DATE'), ('1837', 'DATE'), ('1889', 'DATE'), ('Pfeiffer', 'PERSON'), ('specifie', 'ORG'), ('1o', 'CARDINAL'), ('40.ödeg.', 'MONEY'), ('four to eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('a. dysenteric', 'PERSON')]"
20,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54570x_article_1,article,1918-02-02,"Japanese Steamship Wrecked.
The. Japanese steamship Naha Maru
ran, ona reck off tne Saganoseki-Bungo
Strait on January 29 and sank. The
captain and uhrd officer, with#thirteen
of the crew and twenty passengers are
missing.—Lloyd's.
Cholera Spréading in Crimea.
According to news from Talta, the
epidemic of plague is assuming serious
Proportions. Plague centres are also reported in the Caucasus. The Red Cross
has sent a special train with sanitary
miaterial.—Havas.
General Leman in Paris.
General Leman, the defender of Liége,
arrived in Paris yesterday murning from
Geneva on his way to Havre to confer
with ther Belgian Government. He is
going tö Spain for his health. General
L.eman, is suffering from a disease of the
liver, the. résult of the diet imposéd on
him in Germany.—Intransigeant.","[('Japanese', 'NORP'), ('Japanese', 'NORP'), ('Naha Maru', 'PERSON'), ('ona reck', 'PERSON'), ('Saganoseki-Bungo\nStrait', 'ORG'), ('January 29', 'DATE'), ('twenty', 'CARDINAL'), ('missing.—Lloyd', 'PERSON'), ('Cholera Spréading', 'PERSON'), ('Crimea', 'GPE'), ('Talta', 'ORG'), ('The Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('Leman', 'PERSON'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Leman', 'PERSON'), ('Liége', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('Geneva', 'GPE'), ('Havre', 'NORP'), ('Belgian Government', 'ORG'), ('Spain', 'GPE')]"
21,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t513714_article_45,article,1919-01-10,"Newport Naval Barracks Fire.
Provtniset, R.I., Thursday. — Fire
causing 815.000 damags, destroged one
section of the Neuport Naral barracks.
The lmildings werelused as warchouses,
andwere knorn as Shack Eighteen
Watching for Bombs.
Piitzsperrun, Pa., Thursdag.—Picket
guards are watching all, Government
huildings to prevent a recurrence of the
bomh-throwing episodes, which recently
destroyed privateldwellings of sereral
prominont eitizens.
Wheaton College Opens.
Bosros, Mass., Thursdag.—Wheaton
Callege has opened its“ winter term.
There are no influenza cases. Tho Ir.
brarg is being mored from iho Mary","[('Newport Naval Barracks Fire', 'ORG'), ('Provtniset', 'GPE'), ('R.I.', 'GPE'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('815.000 damags', 'MONEY'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Neuport Naral', 'ORG'), ('Shack Eighteen', 'PERSON'), ('Piitzsperrun', 'GPE'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Wheaton College Opens', 'ORG'), ('Bosros', 'GPE'), ('Mass.', 'GPE'), ('winter', 'DATE'), ('Tho Ir', 'PERSON'), ('Mary', 'PERSON')]"
22,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t514196_article_189,article,1919-02-27,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
Lownow, Wednesday. —During the
week ending February 22 3,046 deaths
were caused by influenza in the 96 towns
of Great Britain having, more thau
50,00 inhabitants, This is'a big increase
over the previous weck, during wlich
1,363 deatlis were recorded.
In the London district the number of
deaths last week was 653, as ’against
272 during the previous weck.
City of Paris statisties for last wech
show that tho total number of deaths
in the capital was 1,894,as against
1,457 during the preceding week and
1,076, the average for the season. Tho
number of deaths ascribed directly. t
influchza is 358.","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Lownow', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('the\nweek ending February 22', 'DATE'), ('3,046', 'CARDINAL'), ('96', 'CARDINAL'), ('Great Britain', 'GPE'), ('1,363', 'CARDINAL'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('653', 'DATE'), ('272', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('1,457', 'CARDINAL'), ('the preceding week', 'DATE'), ('1,076', 'CARDINAL'), ('the season', 'DATE'), ('358', 'CARDINAL')]"
23,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t529395_article_179,article,1919-10-24,"cure indigestion
Indigestion and stomach troubles
are conditions that follow a defective
state of the blood, as in anemia, or
after influenza, or even through lach
of.-healthy exercise and fresh air
Also, indigestion causes the blood to
be deprived of nourishment, so that
there is close connection. between a
weak stomach und bloodlessness, either
heing likely to cause the other.
To dispel indigestion and strengthen
a debilitated 'stomach, néw, good bleod
is necessary, and it has been repeatedly
proved thaß the rich, red blood created
by Dr. Williams' pink pills has a
direct influence on the stomach, digestion and nerves. This new hlood
revives the appetite, restores the
stomach and digestive powers to
heaithy activity, and steadily imparts
strength to those who follow the treatment.
The great value of Dr. Williams
pink pills in, indigestion and ansmia
is demonstrated in the case of Mrs.
Ethel Carline, wife of Mr. G. A. Carline, a coal miner, of 15 Chapel lane,
Hasland, near Chesterfield.
My husband was away in France
for three and a half years,) said
Mrs. Carline, “and returned home at
Christmas last. After my little boy,
Austen, was born, in February. 1916,
I was in poor healthand worried. I
began to think I was never going to
get any better. A doctor told me I
was suffering from chronic indigestion
and anemia. I felt I cöuld not eat,
and what little food I did take disagreed with me. Splitting headaches
tortured me, and I was unable to de
my housework. I took various mediciness, hüt nothing seemed to do me
any good.","[('Indigestion', 'ORG'), ('influenza', 'PERSON'), ('lach', 'GPE'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Williams', 'PERSON'), ('Ethel Carline', 'PERSON'), ('G. A. Carline', 'PERSON'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hasland', 'GPE'), ('Chesterfield', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('three and a half years', 'DATE'), ('Carline', 'PERSON'), ('Christmas', 'DATE'), ('Austen', 'PERSON'), ('February', 'DATE'), ('1916', 'DATE')]"
24,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54015m_article_55,article,1920-04-24,"About a year ago, a law wasadopted
in France requiring every urban community of ten thousand inhabitants or
mors to establish within three years
such plans as to thé municipalities
secmed wise for improvement, embellishment and extension.: The object of
che law, of course, was to follow-in the
wake of' the city-planning movement
Which is already accomplishing remarkably beneficent results in England and-America. All are 'agreed on
the necessity of bringing abeut somné
degree of order in the matter of the
ash-heaps which Tcivie progress'
causes to acchmulate on the outskirts
of cur cities, so that the approaches
mnay take the semblance of some approach to beauty and attractiveness.
Similarly, there is general recognition of the necessity of enlarging and
extending streéts for better communication between the various points in
the city and of creating parks and
open späces, in a word, of ameliorating the conditions crcated by the piling up of thousands and hundreds of
thousands of human beings- to stifle
withinthe limits of a few square
miles.“ For such improvements there
äre impelling reasons'on therscore of
heaith, as on that of esthetics. It has
been well said, for instance, that gardens planted with trees and other open
spaces are the lungs of'all great cities
Unfortunately, it. appears that
those primary and essential objects of
the new Freuch law are overlooked in
certain, plans and projects presented
tor the Paris municipality. To judge
by the explanations and illustrations
exhibited in the Palmarium of the
Bois du Boulogne, the.
ingenious authors proposeto destroyone of the most
beautiful civic perspectives in the
world by erecting a bridge across the
Tuileries Gardens beiween the Seine
and the rue Castiglione
Another
of these plans proposes to build on the
site of the fortifications now being removed and facing the Bois de Boulogne
a number of twelve-storey buildings.
Such structures, plainly, would in
short order become the breeding place
of tuberculosis and other epidemic diseases, besides presenting an impassable
barrier to the passageover Paris of
the slightest breeze from the city’s
great breathing space.
Such so-called improvements would
appear“ to' be far from complying with
the main object of a measure intendec
to improve. thie health and beauty of
the capital. But there is, fortunately,
small chance of their being accepted.","[('About a year ago', 'DATE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('ten thousand', 'CARDINAL'), ('three years', 'DATE'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('Tcivie', 'ORG'), ('thousands and hundreds', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('a few square\nmiles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Freuch', 'PRODUCT'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Bois du Boulogne', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Tuileries Gardens', 'LOC'), ('Seine', 'NORP'), ('the Bois de Boulogne', 'ORG'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('thie health', 'ORG')]"
25,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t526356_article_60,article,1920-12-24,"Major Charles E. S. Webster, of Bethlehem, Pa., wilo. has arrived in Warsaw from
Armenia 10 dircct the attack of the. American
Rech Cross on Polund's
1OH'/1 Cases
of typhus, 
ates that, at the present rate
ol. progress, it will
take
ten
ürs to wipe
out typhus in Poland.
he fever has becoine epidemic through sis years of almost
continuous ligliting, said Dr. Webster.
We must have disinfectants, soap, clean
linen and clothing in great quantities il we
are to make nny impression against thescourge.) Dr. Webster has been in Armenia,
Where lie made a special studg al sanitation
and epidemienl disenses for #the American
Goverument mission.
Ia its work agäinst the iyplais öpidemie,
the American Red-Cröss will co-operate wich
Dr. Emil Godelewski, who has been appointecl hicalth dietater in T’oland. Dr. Godelew'ski is known throughiout Kastern Europe us an expert in hystiene. Ilis writings
on the subjert üre wiclelz known andl u#
usedl #s test-books in nurses' schools and
Hospitals.","[('Charles E. S. Webster', 'PERSON'), ('Bethlehem', 'GPE'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Warsaw', 'GPE'), ('Armenia 10', 'FAC'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Rech Cross', 'ORG'), ('Polund', 'ORG'), ('Cases', 'ORG'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Webster', 'PERSON'), ('Webster', 'PERSON'), ('Armenia', 'GPE'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Goverument', 'ORG'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Emil Godelewski', 'PERSON'), (""Godelew'ski"", 'PERSON'), ('Kastern Europe', 'LOC'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), ('Hospitals', 'FAC')]"
26,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53948b_article_199,article,1920-02-17,"WaksAw. Sunday. —The PPolish Government-has received: from the Alljed
countries“ proposals for energetic, measures to be.täkchlagainst the epidemic
of typhus. whichis decimating certair
parts of Poländ, and particularly the
eastern marshes.
With this end in view. the Allied
Governments have offered Poland a
loan of-S11.,000.000 and disinterested
aid in the supply of pharmaceutica
articles, medical equipments, linen and
other requisitcs. The only condition
laid down bythe Allies is that Poland
should agree to leave the. management
of this humanitarian mission in Allied
hands.
This condition has been discussed by
a commission of thei Diet. where some
were in favor androthers against accepting thé öffer of. the Allics.: Finally
it was agreed to leare the decision of
the duestion to the Goverument.","[('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Alljed', 'ORG'), ('Poländ', 'GPE'), ('Allied', 'ORG'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Allies', 'PERSON'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Allied', 'ORG'), ('thei Diet', 'ORG'), ('Allics', 'NORP'), ('Goverument', 'ORG')]"
27,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539354_article_26,article,1920-02-04,"(BT SPECIAL CABLE TO THE HERALD.)
Wasnieron. Tuesday. — President
Wilson narrowiy escaped an attack of
influenza last week, it became known
in the city to-day. He contracted a
slight cold which threatened to develop into flu, But Dr. Grayson took
every precaution, barring irom the
sick-room an attendaut who was suspected as a carrier of the infiuenzo
germ.
The general health of the President
continues to improre, but his physician said to-day it was unlikely he
would take the proposed southern trip.
As long as he continnes to improre in
Washington Dr. Grayson will not advocate his lcaring çomfortable quarters at the White House for the fatigue of a long trip which might overtax his strength.","[('BT SPECIAL CABLE TO', 'ORG'), ('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Wasnieron', 'GPE'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Wilson', 'ORG'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('Grayson', 'PERSON'), ('Washington', 'GPE'), ('Grayson', 'PERSON'), ('the White House', 'FAC')]"
28,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539354_article_23,article,1920-02-04,"(BT SPECIAL CABIE TO THE HIERALD.)
Nrw. Tonk, Tuesday. — Influenza
cases in New Tork dropped during ihe
past twenty-four hours to 2,673. Despite the earlier optimistic view of
Health Commissioner Copeland regarding the strike'of the firemen in apartment houses, the men and landlords
hare not come to an agreement, and
thie former say they will walk out tomorrow morning.
If this happens it will cause man)
deaths'of persons now.suffering from flu
who will be left withont any heat in
their homes. Commissioner Copeland
still believes a „seitlement is possible
and he is making auother appeal to
both parties in the dispute to-night.","[('BT SPECIAL CABIE', 'ORG'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Influenza', 'NORP'), ('New Tork', 'GPE'), ('twenty-four hours', 'TIME'), ('2,673', 'CARDINAL'), ('Health', 'ORG'), ('Copeland', 'PERSON'), ('tomorrow', 'DATE'), ('morning', 'TIME'), ('Copeland', 'PERSON')]"
29,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539354_article_3,article,1920-02-04,"Daily assertegl that Newberrg used
the rank of Lieutenant-Commander in
tho Navy in making films, ostensiblz
to stimulate navy recruiting, in
reality for an ädvance sehatorial campaign.
Members of the jury are being
treated by a special physician guarding against the flu, wlich has incapacitated several of the defendants, but
which Judge Sessions refused as an
excuse to permit further delay in procceding with the trial.","[('Newberrg', 'ORG'), ('Navy', 'ORG'), ('Sessions', 'PERSON')]"
30,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539354_article_31,article,1920-02-04,"(BT SPECIAL CABLE T0 THE HERALD.)
Nuw Tonk, Tuesday.—The estate of
the late Mr. William Tawkey has
been found upon inventory to valuc
ouly 88,983,000, instead of S40,000,000,
as estimated at the time of his death.
His adopted son, Thomas A. Nawkey,
and the widow divide equally 86,817,
000 between them, their residuary
share when other bequests have been
deducted
Mr.-Tawkev inherited a large estate
from his father and added to it bywise investments, principally in timber land. He was at oue-time owner of
the Detroit Americau Baseball Club.
He died at Augusta, Ga., on March 5
of last year from an attack of flu
while on an automobile trip of the
South.","[('BT SPECIAL CABLE', 'ORG'), ('T0', 'PRODUCT'), ('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Nuw Tonk', 'PERSON'), ('William Tawkey', 'PERSON'), ('88,983,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('S40,000,000', 'PRODUCT'), ('Thomas A. Nawkey', 'PERSON'), ('86,817', 'CARDINAL'), ('000', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Detroit Americau Baseball Club', 'ORG'), ('Augusta', 'GPE'), ('Ga.', 'GPE'), ('March 5\nof last year', 'DATE'), ('South', 'LOC')]"
31,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539354_article_69,article,1920-02-04,"Lond Braon, January 11.—With his
home wrapped in flames, Lew Dockstader, the comedian, lowered the.body
of his dead wile from a second-story
window where sho lay awaiting burial.
Mrs. Dockstader, who was sixty Fears
of age, had died a few hours before the
fire broke out at au carly hour this
morning. She had been ill since
January I, and had nerer fülly recovered from anattack of influenza
Which she suffered last autumn
Dookstader made several trips into
tho burning house to save valuable
papers after the body of his wife hac
been taken to a local undertaking
establishment. The fire. originated in
the ccllar, and the home was badly.
damaged by smoke and water.
Eugene Stovenson, tho comedian's
grändson, wlio was ill with pneumonin
on an upper-foor of the building, was
removed to tho home of a neighbor
by firemen.","[('Lond Braon', 'PERSON'), ('January 11.—With', 'DATE'), ('Lew Dockstader', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Dockstader', 'PERSON'), ('a few hours', 'TIME'), ('carly hour', 'TIME'), ('this\nmorning', 'TIME'), ('January', 'DATE'), ('last autumn', 'DATE'), ('Dookstader', 'PERSON'), ('Eugene Stovenson', 'PERSON'), ('wlio', 'PERSON')]"
32,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t514257_article_175,article,1919-03-05,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
Lornon, Tuesday. — The influenza
epidemic is still on the wanc. Not
only is there a diminution in the number of cases which require medical attendance, but the attacks are also of a
milder type.","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Lornon', 'PERSON'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE')]"
33,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52926z_article_6,article,1919-10-11,"Four
resolütions of specialniôment
sented to the Industrial Conference on
thei resumption of the sittings,which
maythave a far-reäching effect onindustrial conditions in this country. The
sentiment of the conferenceis al determination to havea better understanding between capital and labor
and to, curb. the epidemic of. strikes
wllich are crippling industry inall
parts ofithe country.
Mr. Samuel Gompers, presidenbrof
the-American Federation of. Labor, submitted a resolutionsproviding that the
steel workers-Should. resunfe work immediatelf#rendingiher adjustment of
tholstrike-byrarboard composed of twö
members of each group representing
capital, läborand tlie public. Mr.
Gompers also“presented a resolution
embodying eleren fundamental principles. unanimously approved by te
labor Selégates: Thesewere:—
1. Thei right that wagercärners should","[('Four', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Industrial Conference on\nthei', 'LAW'), ('havea', 'ORG'), ('Samuel Gompers', 'PERSON'), ('the-American Federation', 'ORG'), ('Gompers', 'PERSON'), ('Selégates', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thei', 'PERSON')]"
34,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52926z_article_233,article,1919-10-11,"Lorpör, Friday:— Almost every
otherperson one meets hasaserere
cold. This. is,leading neryouspeople
to believesthat another-influenza#epidemichisbéginning.ThérMilistry of
Health;vhowéreras reassuringauthis
point.  hereis nothinginithe mature 6ffanfinflnènzat cpidemic, #t
SaysItis truesthat, erery other person hasa cold. but thattis not abnormal for the time offyear, and tliere
is not#theislightest indication of any
retürnofthe-scourge that- proved so
deadlylastyspring.
Typhoid in Sweden.
Srocknorhr, Thursday.—An epidemic
of typhoid#ferer at-Gothenburg is assumingalarmingproportions, aboni
300 cases'having'alrcady;beeninotified.","[('Lorpör', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('6ffanfinflnènzat', 'CARDINAL'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), ('SaysItis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Typhoid', 'ORG'), ('Sweden', 'GPE'), ('Srocknorhr', 'ORG'), ('300', 'CARDINAL')]"
35,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t52910t_article_100,article,1919-09-25,"Mapkru, Wednesday. — Several cases
of grippe—Spanish, of course—are reported in the capital and in the province of Madrid, the most serious cases
occurring in one of the military barracks. as in last year's epidemic. Although the authorities declare that
these are ouly isolated cases and that
meusures hiare been taken to prerent
thesprend of an epidemie, people
here are alarmed.","[('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Madrid', 'GPE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), (""last year's"", 'DATE')]"
36,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51433w_article_104,article,1919-03-13,"There is o, further fall to record in the
terribly high death-rate of-Paris, according to the figures of the Munidipal
Stat stical Servics. Thus for the tenth
week of the year tie total of deaths
was 1,440 in cömparison with 1,687 for
the preceding week, and 1,071 the ordinarv average for the season. Grippe
was responsible for 296 deaths and 353
were credited to diseases of the. réspiratory organs. The births of 571 children were registered during ther week
and 614 marriages were celébrated.
HUNGER DISEASE GERM FOUND.
(FROM THE HERALD'S CORRESTONDENr.)
Lospos, Wednesday.—According to a
despatch from Copenhagen' a telegram
has been received thière from Vienna
which savs that at a meeting öf the
Medical Scciety a. leading doctdh, read
à Paper demionstrating the presence of
a hunger germ in ihe bodies of victims
of the famine in Austria.
Experiments have shown##that this
germ attacked the bones of fht body
and was causing a great epidemic.","[('Paris', 'GPE'), ('the tenth\nweek of the year', 'DATE'), ('1,440', 'CARDINAL'), ('1,687', 'CARDINAL'), ('the preceding week', 'DATE'), ('1,071', 'CARDINAL'), ('the season', 'DATE'), ('296', 'CARDINAL'), ('353', 'CARDINAL'), ('571', 'CARDINAL'), ('614', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lospos', 'PERSON'), ('Copenhagen', 'ORG'), ('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Austria', 'GPE')]"
37,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54679z_article_5,article,1918-05-22,"Last Saturday. there. was an epidemic
of fires in Germäny. Big outbreaks oceurred at the Siemens Schukert works
inBerlin, at the Sagan paper mills and
the station and forage substitute works
of the village of Stronnaubruch, near
Bromberg. The village was almost wipea
aut.—Petit Parisien,
Mesopotamia Communiqué,
The Turks in Mesopotamia have shown
nosign of activity since they were repulsed, on May 16, beyond the Lower
Aab, when they abandoned large quantilics of war material. The occupation
of Karkuk procceds without interruption. On the Tigris our mounted troops
hare advanced as far as Fatha.—Britishe
Oficial","[('Last Saturday', 'DATE'), ('Germäny', 'GPE'), ('the Siemens Schukert', 'ORG'), ('Sagan', 'PERSON'), ('Stronnaubruch', 'GPE'), ('Bromberg', 'GPE'), ('Parisien', 'PERSON'), ('Mesopotamia Communiqué', 'ORG'), ('Turks', 'NORP'), ('Mesopotamia', 'GPE'), ('May 16', 'DATE'), ('Karkuk', 'PERSON'), ('Tigris', 'ORG')]"
38,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51429g_article_21,article,1919-03-09,"(SPEOIAT, TELEGRAN TO THE HERATD.)
From CAMERON MACKENZIE
Wnsaw (via Vienna), Friday.—It. is
practically impossible to writo of conditions as ther exist here in Poland
these days without writing of direst
misery and suffering. Ifit is not of
unemployment, hungeror the poison of
Bolshevism thabrone learns, it is of the
rayages of discäse.
According to figures collectedby the
Department of Health, there are now
no fewer than 100,000 cases of typhus in
this conntrg of 25,000,000 population.
Little is being done, because littiescan
be done on. acconnt of lack of facilities
to chcck the spread of thé cpidemic.
The percentage of deaths is, of course,
under the circumstances, appalling.
In addition te this typhus epidemic,
there is a tremendous amount of influenza and pneuionia; Among thß children trachoma is very prevalent. The
Government has not yet verfected its
machinery for recording vital statisties,
but, passing along the streets, one's
cyes furnish abundant eridence of the","[('SPEOIAT', 'ORG'), ('HERATD', 'ORG'), ('Wnsaw', 'PERSON'), ('Vienna', 'GPE'), ('Poland', 'GPE'), ('these days', 'DATE'), ('the\nDepartment of Health', 'ORG'), ('no fewer than 100,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('25,000,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('pneuionia', 'GPE'), ('The\nGovernment', 'ORG')]"
39,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51414n_article_187,article,1919-02-22,"The American boxing team which has
just completed a tour in Italy, under
the direction of Mr. Jimmie Bronson,
of the T.M.C.A., returned to Paris yesterday, and will make the final stand of
exhibition dates at the Cirque de Paris
to-day.
Lieutenant Harry Leighton was in
command of thesteam, all of whom, with
the exception of Gene Payo, who is still
down with “flu'' at Venice, have returned safoly.
Exhibitions were staged at Milan,
Florenco, Bologna, Rome, Venico,
Genoa and at numerous army camps
and a particularly notable show was
given in the presence of 5,000 American,
French, British and Italian sailors on
board the Italian battleship Umberto.","[('American', 'NORP'), ('Italy', 'GPE'), ('Jimmie Bronson', 'PERSON'), ('T.M.C.A.', 'GPE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('the Cirque de Paris', 'FAC'), ('Harry Leighton', 'PERSON'), ('Gene Payo', 'PERSON'), ('Venice', 'GPE'), ('Milan', 'GPE'), ('Florenco', 'PERSON'), ('Bologna', 'GPE'), ('Rome', 'GPE'), ('Venico', 'GPE'), ('Genoa', 'PERSON'), ('5,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('French', 'LANGUAGE'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Italian', 'NORP'), ('Umberto', 'GPE')]"
40,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53301m_article_78,article,1918-11-08,"FRON THE HERALD'S CORRESPOKDENr.)
Lorpon, Thursday.—A distressing influenza tragedy oecurred at Stowmarket. A baker. named Leonard Sitch
murdered his wife and two sons and
afterwards committed- suleide
Mr. Sitch was attacked by the malady
last week, and erentually the whole
family were obliged to take to their
beds
A neigbber discovered Sitch's body
hanging from a line in the bedroom, and
the wife and children were afterwards
found battered to death in another
room. A chopper and bayonet were
found nearbr¬","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Lorpon', 'PERSON'), ('Thursday.—A', 'GPE'), ('influenza', 'PERSON'), ('Stowmarket', 'GPE'), ('Leonard Sitch', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sitch', 'PERSON'), ('last week', 'DATE'), ('Sitch', 'ORG')]"
41,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539471_article_2,article,1920-02-16,"Switzerland Enters ther League
BEndn.—t is öfficially announced
that Switzerland has becn admitted
into the League of Nations, which will
guarantee her neutrality.
Doctors to NotifyGrippe.'
In order that adeguste measures
may be taken against influenza in the
Paris district, the authorities have
asked doctors to.notify all cases.
Hungary Objects to“Republic.
Hungary inits comments on the
Conference peace ferms takes exception to the words“Hungarian Republic! andwishes to substitute
simply Hüngarg
Will Move for Irish Freedom
Nrw Tonk: —.Senator J. Hamilton
Lewis, of Chicago,is said to have
told'the-Irish. Fellowship Club that as
soon as the United States has qualified asa member of the League of
Nations President Wilson intends to
raise in the Council of the League the
question of the right of Treland te
self-determination","[('Switzerland', 'GPE'), ('Switzerland', 'GPE'), ('the League of Nations', 'ORG'), ('NotifyGrippe', 'ORG'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE'), ('the words“Hungarian Republic', 'GPE'), ('Hüngarg', 'PERSON'), ('J. Hamilton\nLewis', 'PERSON'), ('Chicago', 'GPE'), (""told'the-Irish"", 'NORP'), ('Fellowship Club', 'ORG'), ('the United States', 'GPE'), ('the League of\nNations', 'ORG'), ('Wilson', 'PERSON'), ('the Council of the League', 'ORG'), ('Treland', 'ORG')]"
42,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53924j_article_17,article,1920-01-24,"(BT SPECIAL CABLE 10 THE IIBRALD.)
Nrw Tonk, Friday.—
The epidemic
of influcnza is spreading rapidly both
in this city and Chicago, where new
victims number thousands. During the
past twenty-four hours
there were
1.000 new cases in this city, and in
Obicago the number was 2,226. Ten
per cent. of Chicago's police forco is
down with che cpidemic, and the tobal
cases in that city now number 10,000
Health Commissioner Copeland, of
New Vork, has asked an emergency
appropriation of 680,000 to fight the
epidemic. He has appealed tosthe prolnbition oflicials for the sale of whiskey by physicjans and druggists as a
mneans of fighting the discase.
Commissioner Copeland said:My
reason for making the appeai is not
founded on auy personal opinion of
the value of wliskey in influchza cases,
but because many repatable physicians
feel it is an important. drug and should
be made available in this crisis.
AII casc of iufluenza,' he said,
Fare milder than thosc of last Fear
and ofshorter duration. It would seem
that ther germ has outworn its virulence. The discase this gear is less
frequently followed by pneumonia than
was the case a Fear ago.?
The commissioner said that the shortage of nurses was incxplidable in
view of the fact that the army staffs
have been demobilised. He said that
thé city's hospitals had 4,000 vacant
beds.","[('BT SPECIAL CABLE', 'ORG'), ('10', 'CARDINAL'), ('IIBRALD', 'ORG'), ('Nrw Tonk', 'ORG'), ('Friday', 'DATE'), ('Chicago', 'GPE'), ('thousands', 'CARDINAL'), ('twenty-four hours', 'QUANTITY'), ('1.000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Obicago', 'GPE'), ('2,226', 'CARDINAL'), ('Ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chicago', 'GPE'), ('10,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Health', 'ORG'), ('Copeland', 'PERSON'), ('New Vork', 'GPE'), ('680,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Copeland', 'PERSON'), ('AII', 'ORG'), ('4,000', 'CARDINAL')]"
43,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53924j_article_21,article,1920-01-24,"New. Tonx, Friday.—Tokio dospatches announce that Prince Yashishito, sccond son of tho Emperor of
Japan, is seriously ill with iniluenza,
Another despatch from Tokio says
that terrifying progress is being made
by the influenza epidemic in Japan.
In Tokio alono there have been 200,-
000 cases, with 1,700 deaths. Everyone
is using serums and masks.","[('Tonx', 'ORG'), ('Friday.—Tokio dospatches', 'PERSON'), ('Prince Yashishito', 'PERSON'), ('Japan', 'GPE'), ('Tokio', 'ORG'), ('Japan', 'GPE'), ('Tokio', 'ORG'), ('200,-', 'CARDINAL'), ('1,700', 'CARDINAL')]"
44,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54694z_article_207,article,1918-06-06,"Lord Chancellor of Treland.
Sir James Campbell, Lord Chief Justice of Treland, has been appointed Lord
Chancellor. for Treland, replacing Sir
Ignatius John O’Brien, who has resignéd
and been raised tothe peerage.—Petit
Parisien.
Madrid“Convalescent.'
Therepidemie of influenza is diminishing in Madrid and in the provinces, with
tlie exception of the, western districts.
Jufluenza bacilli have been-discovered in
most- cases, but thoser of meningitis have
also been recognized.—Havas.
Fatal Collision in Air.
Two aeroplanes, one piloted by Adjudant Gaillauroux and the other by M.
Hutin, accompanied by M. Flamand, a
pupil aviator, collided yesterday while
landing at an aerodromé near Mäcon
(Saone-et-Loire). All three men were
killed.— Figaro.
American, Help in the Creuse.
The American. Red Cross has just presented to the Departmental Committee
af the Refugees in the-Creuse clothing
and shoes to the value of several tens of
thousands of francs and the sum of
37,000fr. for inhabitants of the Creuse
vho have suffered by the war.—Havas.","[('Treland', 'ORG'), ('James Campbell', 'PERSON'), ('Treland', 'ORG'), ('Treland', 'ORG'), ('Ignatius', 'ORG'), ('John O’Brien', 'PERSON'), ('Parisien', 'PERSON'), ('Therepidemie', 'PERSON'), ('Madrid', 'GPE'), ('Fatal Collision', 'ORG'), ('Two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Adjudant Gaillauroux', 'ORG'), ('M.\nHutin', 'PERSON'), ('M. Flamand', 'PERSON'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('Mäcon', 'GPE'), ('three', 'CARDINAL'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Creuse', 'ORG'), ('American', 'NORP'), ('Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('the Departmental Committee', 'ORG'), ('several tens', 'CARDINAL'), ('thousands of francs', 'MONEY'), ('37,000fr', 'CARDINAL'), ('Creuse', 'ORG')]"
45,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t531876_article_47,article,1918-07-17,"(FROM THE RERALD'S CORRESPONDENT.)
Lorpos, Tuesday.—Queen Amélie, who
has been ordered a complete rest by her
medical adviser, is making satisfactory
progress.
The Marquis of Lansdowne is so far
improved as to be able to leave his room.
Viscountess Campden has undergone
a successful operation at 1 Belgrave
place. Her progress is quite satisfactory.
Sir. Frederick Milver is suffering from
severe brain strain and has been ordered to take a complete rest for some
Weeks.
Brigadier-General Page-Croft is confined to bed by influenza.
Lieutenant-Colonel Sir Henry Trotter's condition shows no change and is
satisfactory.
The engagement is announced between
Sub-Lieutenant the Hon. Frank Hopwood, R.N.V.R., younger-son of Lord
Southborough, and Audrey, younger
daughter of Mr. and Mrs. E. G. Money,
of Ashurstwood House, East Grinstead.
The engagement is announced of Captain A. V. Barclay, King’s African Rifles, of Lumbwa, British East Africa
and Katherine, only daughter of Mr
Arthur V. Willeox and Mrs. Willcos, of
Lisnabrucka, Recess, County Galway,
and Haverford, Pa.
A marriage has been arranged between
Mr. Keith Edwards, Scots Guards, and
Mrs. Osborne Raherts. twin sister cf the
Hon. Mrs. Melton Astley and widow of
Mr. Osbarne Poberts and daughter of
the late General. G. A. Strover, Com-
missioner of Pegu. Burma.","[('Lorpos', 'ORG'), ('Amélie', 'PERSON'), ('The Marquis of Lansdowne', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Viscountess Campden', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Frederick Milver', 'PERSON'), ('Weeks', 'DATE'), ('Brigadier-General Page-Croft', 'ORG'), ('influenza', 'PERSON'), (""Henry Trotter's"", 'PERSON'), ('Frank Hopwood', 'PERSON'), ('R.N.V.R.', 'ORG'), ('Audrey', 'PERSON'), ('E. G. Money', 'PERSON'), ('Ashurstwood House', 'ORG'), ('East Grinstead', 'GPE'), ('King’s African Rifles', 'ORG'), ('Lumbwa', 'GPE'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('East Africa', 'GPE'), ('Katherine', 'ORG'), ('Arthur V. Willeox', 'PERSON'), ('Willcos', 'PERSON'), ('Lisnabrucka', 'GPE'), ('Recess', 'GPE'), ('County Galway', 'PERSON'), ('Haverford', 'GPE'), ('Pa.', 'GPE'), ('Keith Edwards', 'PERSON'), ('Scots Guards', 'PERSON'), ('Osborne Raherts', 'PERSON'), ('Hon', 'ORG'), ('Melton Astley', 'PERSON'), ('Osbarne', 'PERSON'), ('G. A. Strover', 'PERSON'), ('Pegu', 'GPE')]"
46,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t531876_article_80,article,1918-07-17,"(FROAT THE HERALD'S CORRESPONDENT.)
LoxnoN. Tuesday. — Major Sir Archibald Leonard Lucas-Tooth, Bart., Honourable Artillery Company, of Holme
Lacy, Herefordshire, and Kamernka,
New South Wales, died of pneumonia,
following influenza, on the 12th inst.
at a hospital abroad. He was the onlv
surviring son af the late Sir Robert
Luras-Tooth. Burt, and uf #len Lady
Lura“-Toeth. af 143 Piccadille und mar
ried in 191n Tosa. ruunget Jaughter uf
V. and 1## Hon Urs Bovill.
Crlonel J. C. Cavendish.
The feath is annonnced of Colonel
Jumes Charles Carendish, of Darley
House, Derby, in his eightieth gear. He
was a son of the late Lord George Cavendish and second cousin of the Duke of
Devonshire. After service in the Crimea he retired from the army in 1867
with the rank of captain. Settling in
Derbyshire. he identified himself vrominently with public affairs. In 1891 he
became A.D.C. to Queen Victoria. He
was unmarried.","[('FROAT', 'ORG'), ('HERALD', 'GPE'), ('CORRESPONDENT', 'ORG'), ('Tuesday', 'DATE'), ('Archibald Leonard', 'PERSON'), ('Bart', 'ORG'), ('Honourable Artillery Company', 'ORG'), ('Holme\nLacy, Herefordshire', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Kamernka', 'PERSON'), ('New South Wales', 'GPE'), ('the 12th', 'DATE'), ('Robert\nLuras-Tooth', 'PERSON'), ('143', 'CARDINAL'), ('mar\n', 'PERSON'), ('191n', 'CARDINAL'), ('Jaughter', 'GPE'), ('Hon Urs Bovill', 'PERSON'), ('Jumes Charles Carendish', 'PERSON'), ('Darley', 'ORG'), ('House', 'ORG'), ('Derby', 'GPE'), ('eightieth', 'ORDINAL'), ('George Cavendish', 'PERSON'), ('second', 'ORDINAL'), ('Devonshire', 'GPE'), ('Crimea', 'ORG'), ('1867', 'DATE'), ('1891', 'DATE'), ('A.D.C.', 'ORG'), ('Queen Victoria', 'PERSON')]"
47,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53276v_article_63,article,1918-10-14,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
Lonnow, Sunday. — The epidemic of
influenza is still unchecked. According
to theDaily Express“’ twenty-eight
schools in Glasgow are closed because
ofrthe prevalence of the disease among
the children. All the elementary schools
in Redhill and Exeter also have. been
closed
At Ixeter several deaths have been
reported from the disease. There have
Been two deaths of children from infiuenza at Wood Green. The schcols hare
also been closed here. The districts of
Hornsey and Tottenham, nearby, report
many cases of the grippe among children.
Mr. John Clark Neil, director of
Messrs. J. and P. Coats, Limited, who
is dead at Largs, is among the many
victims.","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Lonnow', 'GPE'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('theDaily Express', 'ORG'), ('twenty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Glasgow', 'GPE'), ('Redhill', 'PERSON'), ('Exeter', 'PERSON'), ('Ixeter', 'FAC'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Wood Green', 'LOC'), ('Hornsey', 'PERSON'), ('Tottenham', 'GPE'), ('John Clark Neil', 'PERSON'), ('J.', 'PERSON'), ('Limited', 'ORG'), ('Largs', 'ORG')]"
48,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53912n_article_188,article,1920-01-12,"Poses, Sunday. — An outbrcak of
influenza liere hus caused several
deaths.","[('Sunday', 'DATE')]"
49,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53287f_article_198,article,1918-10-25,"enoügh to stand for a clöse-quarter
combat, at. some places. Z. fresh division, the Sth, brought up to relieve the
44ch, and battalions“of the 17th Reserve, also contributed to thie number
of prisoners. Nearly a tliousand were
collected on the Fourth Army's front
during the early hours of the morning.
General Horne's First Army, astride
the Scheldt, is at tlie very edge of Valenciennes. It has occupied La Sentinelle and Saint-Waast-Haut, west of
the town, and Beuvrages, on the west
bank of the river aboreit. The forest
of Raismes, three miles north of Valenciennes, has been évacuated by the
enem.
Civilians found. by our advaneing
forces in the villages west of Valenciennes have had au unpieasant time
owing to the obstinach of. the Hun. Haspres, was divided between tho opposing
fürces for some time and the seven hundred inhabitants süffered from the German artillery. Thiant, south-east, of
Denain, was in a similär predicament
until the enemy was forced to fall back.
We cleared tse last of the machine-gunners out ofthe houses yesterday and
relcased che inhabitants from their
cellars.
Feeding Civilians.
The problem of. cariug for the large
civilian population left in the wake of
the.retreating German army is#a serious
one. At Saint-Amand, over fifteen hundred French people are suffering from
Spanish influenza'' and cännot be
moved. Last night the town was bombarded with gas shells and anumber of
thé invalids was gassed in the cellars.
In one narrow British sector 42,000
eivilians must be fed. The population of
Denain is for the moment entirely dependent on the troops for sustenance.
These. people arc completelg destitute
and many of#them without sufficient
clothing. They endured great privations
during the final days of the German cecupätion and until the arrival of the
Britisharm)
Between Tourpai and Valenciennes
the bank of-the Scheldt has been reached
at' several points: I hear that there is
very littlé change in'the. Flanders front.
The enemy is showing great activity
along the line of the Scheldt-and-he is
still endeavoring to establish a defensive line on'the high ground east 5
the river.","[('enoügh', 'ORG'), ('Sth', 'PRODUCT'), (""the Fourth Army's"", 'ORG'), ('the early hours of the morning', 'TIME'), ('Horne', 'PERSON'), ('First Army', 'ORG'), ('Scheldt', 'GPE'), ('Valenciennes', 'NORP'), ('La Sentinelle', 'FAC'), ('Saint-Waast-Haut', 'ORG'), ('Beuvrages', 'PERSON'), ('the west\nbank', 'ORG'), ('Raismes', 'ORG'), ('three miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Valenciennes', 'NORP'), ('Civilians', 'ORG'), ('Valenciennes', 'NORP'), ('Hun', 'PERSON'), ('seven hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('south-east', 'GPE'), ('Denain', 'PERSON'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('che inhabitants', 'ORG'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Saint-Amand', 'FAC'), ('over fifteen hundred', 'CARDINAL'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Last night', 'TIME'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('British', 'NORP'), ('42,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Denain', 'PERSON'), ('the final days', 'DATE'), ('German', 'NORP'), ('Tourpai', 'PERSON'), ('Valenciennes', 'PRODUCT'), ('Scheldt', 'GPE'), ('Scheldt', 'GPE')]"
50,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53287f_article_202,article,1918-10-25,"Howerer, the United States has sorfar
got off more easily than Great. Britain,
where Nla grippe'“ of the French is Sinfuenza,'' popularly. known as #flu.) In
London'thé districts most affected are
Woolwich, Briston, Lambeth and Clapham, and'the sufferers include all classes,
especially workers,bobbies'' and firemeu. At-Gillingham, West, nearly 1,000
school children are down with the discase. The epidemie is-spreading at an
alarming ratein Glasgow. Last geek
thero werc 510 deaths from grippe and
pneumonia, éömparec with 440 the. previous, week. In Dublin, last weck 101
deaths occhrred as aresult of grippe,
and fiftg-eight from (pneumonia.
Neutral Séandinavin has not escäped
Copenhagenis especially hard hit, and
the Minister of Public: Welfare has ordered all theatres and places of amusement clösed. South America and South
Africa, are also having cho grippe. Johannesburg reports that 10,000 South
Africaus are suffering from the malady,
and Rio de Jaheireland Buenos Aires
are busy counting their patients.","[('the United States', 'GPE'), ('Great', 'GPE'), ('Britain', 'GPE'), ('Nla', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Sinfuenza', 'ORG'), ('Woolwich', 'GPE'), ('Briston', 'GPE'), ('Lambeth', 'PERSON'), ('Clapham', 'PERSON'), ('West', 'LOC'), ('nearly 1,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('Glasgow', 'PERSON'), ('510', 'CARDINAL'), ('440', 'CARDINAL'), ('previous, week', 'DATE'), ('Dublin', 'GPE'), ('101', 'CARDINAL'), ('Neutral Séandinavin', 'PERSON'), ('Copenhagenis', 'PRODUCT'), ('Welfare', 'ORG'), ('South America', 'LOC'), ('South', 'LOC'), ('Africa', 'LOC'), ('Johannesburg', 'GPE'), ('10,000', 'CARDINAL'), ('South\nAfricaus', 'NORP'), ('Rio de Jaheireland', 'ORG'), ('Buenos Aires', 'PERSON')]"
51,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53287f_article_196,article,1918-10-25,"Owing to the epidémic of grippe,
mpon the advice of the Geunvil of Hygiene of the Departmeutlof thre Sarthe,
the: manifestation at Le. Maus organized by#the Lafayette and Wilbur
Wright Committce fer Sinday next has
been postponed, no date being fixed.
The object was to ceiehrate the hundredth anniversary of che cléction of
General Lafayette to the Chamber of
Deputies and at the same time the
Aeroplane. öxperiments of Mr. Wilbur
Wright in the department.
At the manifestation, Mr. William G.
Sharp, American Ampassador, was to
be present, as well as M. Jules Cambon, M. Viviani, M. Painleré, representatives of the French and Amerscan
Headquarters Staff und of the aero
clubs of. France, Italj-, Grcat Britzin
and America","[('the Geunvil of Hygiene', 'ORG'), ('the Departmeutlof thre Sarthe', 'LOC'), ('Le.', 'FAC'), ('Lafayette', 'NORP'), ('Wilbur\nWright Committce', 'PERSON'), ('Sinday', 'DATE'), ('hundredth', 'CARDINAL'), ('Lafayette', 'PERSON'), ('the Chamber of\nDeputies', 'ORG'), ('Aeroplane', 'GPE'), ('Wilbur', 'PERSON'), ('Wright', 'PERSON'), ('William G.\n', 'PERSON'), ('Sharp', 'ORG'), ('American Ampassador', 'ORG'), ('M. Jules Cambon', 'PERSON'), ('M. Viviani', 'PERSON'), ('M. Painleré', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Grcat Britzin', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'GPE')]"
52,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53287f_article_197,article,1918-10-25,"To rur Entron or guE HERArn:—
Barcelona, Spain.
I.sco in reading in the Nrm Yonx
Hrnarn that you call the malady now
raging“Spanish influenza.! I am very
sorry to tell you that this iliness has
nothing at all to do with Spain. I
comes not only from France, but from
all the countries engaged in the war.
Of the#whole world Spain is the least
punished by this terrible disease. I hope
Fou will be so kind as tochange the
name of this epidemie,a name that has
only been given bn the enemies of Spain.
MAROUESA. DE SAN RoMAN DE ArAEA","[('Entron', 'PERSON'), ('Barcelona', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('raging“Spanish', 'NORP'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Fou', 'ORG'), ('Spain', 'GPE'), ('MAROUESA', 'ORG'), ('DE SAN RoMAN DE ArAEA', 'ORG')]"
53,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51456c_article_94,article,1919-04-05,"The greatest danger from an attack
of the grip, or influenza, is affer the
scute stage is over, when the lowered
vitality makes tho system an easy pres
for any germ disease to#which it is cxposed. The debility resulting from an
attack of the grip is so versistent thaß,
if the blood is not built up and the
strength restored, in may last for
months and years. That this is unnecessary is shown by the experience of
Mrs. Laura M. Van Scoy, who lives at
No. 204 Thorpe street, Danbury, Conn.
Shs says:—
I had a severs attack of grip, and
before I had fully recovered rheumatism set in and termested me for three
months. I was in a badly run-dogn
state. Soon after it began I was so lame
for a week that I could hardly walk
It kept growing steadily worse and
pretty scon I actually couldn't walk.
At last I had to gire up completely and
for three weeks I was obliged to keep
to my bed. My kuees were so stiff I
couldn't bend them and. iny hands wero
perfectly helpless. Then the pains began
to threaten my hcart and thoroughly
alarmed me.","[('thaß', 'GPE'), ('months', 'DATE'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('Laura M. Van Scoy', 'PERSON'), ('204', 'CARDINAL'), ('Thorpe', 'NORP'), ('Danbury', 'GPE'), ('Conn.', 'GPE'), ('three\nmonths', 'DATE'), ('a week', 'DATE'), ('three weeks', 'DATE')]"
54,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t528585_article_198,article,1919-08-04,"Losrog, Saturday.—The Rer., W.
W. Perreti, superintendent of tlie
Moravian ölission in Labrador, who
has returned from that counfry to his
hôme at Malmesbury, tells: a moving
story of harrowing experiences during
the influenza epidemic on the-Labrador coast.
At Hebron, the northernmost village,
out of a population of 220 there are but
seventy survivors. At Okak, fifty miles
south, only fifty-nine were left out of
266.All these deaths were due to
influenza, But at Nain and Hopedalee,
Mr. Perrett’s station, smallpox and
measles accounted for forty-eight
more. The influenza was brought to
Labrador bn a sailor on board the mission steamer Harmony, wllich left
about the middle of October. Later the
Rev. S.- M. Stewart, of the Colonial
and Coutinental ölission, was travelling northward by dog-sledge, and on
arriving at a sealing place near Okak
was surprised at seeing no, signs of
human hte. He looked through the
windon of a house, and was korrified to
see it full of dead Eskimos. The next
day hé went on to Okak, and found
practicaliy the same thing—nearly all
the inhabitanis dead. The mortuary
was filled with bodies, and then Eskimo
houses were used in, which to put the
dead.","[('W.\nW. Perreti', 'PERSON'), ('Moravian', 'NORP'), ('Labrador', 'GPE'), ('Malmesbury', 'ORG'), ('Hebron', 'GPE'), ('220', 'CARDINAL'), ('Okak', 'ORG'), ('fifty miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('only fifty-nine', 'CARDINAL'), ('266.All', 'CARDINAL'), ('Nain and Hopedalee', 'FAC'), ('Perrett', 'PERSON'), ('forty-eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Labrador', 'PERSON'), ('the middle of October', 'DATE'), ('S.- M. Stewart', 'PERSON'), ('Colonial', 'ORG'), ('Coutinental', 'ORG'), ('Okak', 'ORG'), ('Eskimos', 'PERSON'), ('The next\nday', 'DATE'), ('Okak', 'ORG'), ('Eskimo', 'PERSON')]"
55,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53194j_article_132,article,1918-07-24,"AbtsTERDAm, Tuesday.—Word has been
received here that Berlin is suffering
from a serious epidemie of typhoid
fever. The police authorities believe
that the epidemic was caused by impurities in the milk sold in the municipal milkshops.—Havas.","[('Tuesday.—Word', 'PERSON'), ('Berlin', 'GPE'), ('milkshops.—Havas', 'PRODUCT')]"
56,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t54045f_article_21,article,1920-05-25,"M. Paul Deschanel, the French President,
icho leit Paris by special train from the Gare
Sunday night to unveil
sie Lyon at 9.3
ihe momumient set up at Montbrison (Loire)
i memory ol the aviator, Scnator Reymond,
ccident during the night that
wet with
scrious consequences.
The
nicht hare had
Presitient seil from the train on torthe railnzd embankment, but sustained only stight
ijuries, and was able to return 1o Paris. last
gight by automobile
Among the party in ihe Presidential train
gere M. Stecg, Minister of the Interior; M.
p. E. Flandin, Under-Secretary for Aeronauties; General Pénclon and several Senators
ind Deputies. The President, who was suflering from a slighit attack ol influenza, retred to his slecping. compartment at abont
ien o'chck when the train had passed lhe
Taris suburhs. The compartment, which was
rot much more than two Fards schare, contained no othier furniture than a small bed
and an arnichair. Ifs two windows were
flosed to prevent draughts. The President's
vaiet had received orders not to awaken him
mffl ihe train, reached Roanne in the
morning.
Uuable to Sleep.
During the night ihe President, although
je had felt very drowsy, was unable lo sicep,
und after a time“ he found that the air in the
Hutle compartment was intolcrably close and
opfressive. He rang for his valet to open
he windows, but as hie did not appear immeMately, M. Deschanel got up and went to the
seerer one to open it himself. The window
ansisted of two sashes, the upper one fixed
zn the lower falling into a slot, leaving an
Gening measuring zlt. Sin. by ift. Sin.
Spparently the window sash was very ditficult to move and the President had to
meke a great effort to open it. Probably
eercome by the sudden inrush of cold air
end perhaps by the rocking of the train
atche moment the window fell, he lost his
lalnce and fell oüt. Nobody was awarc
Wüe accident, and thie train went on as il
Fuing had happened, the occupants dislting that the President was missing
#whien it Stopped at Roanne at about
o'clock in the morning.
lhe President fell out of the train about
ien minutes before midnight at alonely
part ot the line nearly eight nüles from
Montargis and seventy miles Irom Paris.
Fortunately ihe train was not travelling at
full spced, as the driver had. reccived instruclions to go slowly in order not to reach
Roanne too scon and thus to give M. Deschanel time for a long slecp. The spced
was probably not more, than 2s miles an
haur at the time of the accident.
Another fortünate circumstance to which
he President perhaps owes his lise was
hat there was a great deal of light sand
alung that part of the linc. He lell very
heavily, but although much bruised did not
ise consciousness. Alter lying beside the
ine for somie minutes the President redrered from the shock sufficiently to be
sure that he was not severely injured. He
chen stood up, and moving away from the
fails began to walk along the line.
Walking Along Track.
M. Deschanel, who was in his pyjamas,
#n walked for more than a mile, says the
Iatin,“ when he met a platclayer. The
scht ol a man, clad only in light-colored
jamas, coming suddenly cut ol the darkt8, considerably astonished the workman.
That on carth arc you doing on the linc
sie that??' he asked, and when M. Desdnel replied, “My friend,I am the PresiMol the Republic,' he burst out laughiNind said ironically,Like that! in night
%, walking along thie line in ihc open
sury at Lorcy 1'
it Lorcy?'' qucried the President.“Ves,
aore than seven miles from Montargis.!
bat, what time is it, then?? #It’s ten
minates past midnight.“. I leit Paris last
ngit by special train and have fallen out
G m compartment,“' oxplained M. Deschanel.
And you have broken nothing?'
J0, I am only bruised. I should like vou
#g0 with me to the nearest station, so thät
miy telephone. I assure you that I am
J. Paul Deschanel, President of the Refallie,1
„res, ges, of course, replied the cmployé.
in order not to upsct you, I agrec with
as vou cannot be verz' warm and miust
been shaken up in falling from the
I am going to take you home with
Tou can rest there, and as soon as it
au.
haire
trai
Fdy, we shall sce what to do.
fresident and platclayer then set out foFiher and soon arrived at a grade crossing
A Lorcy station.My wise is the gateEper, explained the employé. Come into
litle home. I will wake my wile and
will take
care ol you and give you someWart
* Deschanel went in and when the gateer appeared he said,Madam, your-husM will not beliere thät I am the Presi„M ol che Republic., 1 have fallen from
train. T'nls
a good iook at me. Ilave
e
seen n photograph of M. Pauf
er
replici thie woman, Sbut you
much like him.?
„is frue I am in prjamas,' answered
resident, Thut that,docs not prevent
om being the Chief of State
the plalelayer then whispered to his wile
#ho then said:es, my good man, you
ihe President of the Republic, but instead
falking like this, come and let me was
Jour hands und face are serafched.","[('M. Paul Deschanel', 'PERSON'), ('French', 'NORP'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('Gare', 'ORG'), ('Sunday night', 'TIME'), ('Lyon', 'PERSON'), ('9.3', 'CARDINAL'), ('Montbrison (Loire', 'ORG'), ('Scnator Reymond', 'PERSON'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('1o', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('M. Stecg', 'PERSON'), ('Interior', 'ORG'), ('M.\n', 'PERSON'), ('E. Flandin', 'PERSON'), ('Aeronauties', 'ORG'), ('General Pénclon', 'ORG'), ('Taris', 'ORG'), ('more than two', 'CARDINAL'), ('Fards', 'ORG'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('awaken', 'PERSON'), ('Roanne', 'ORG'), ('the\nmorning', 'TIME'), ('the night', 'TIME'), ('Hutle', 'LOC'), ('M. Deschanel', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sin', 'ORG'), ('Sin', 'PERSON'), ('Wüe', 'GPE'), ('Fuing', 'ORG'), ('#', 'CARDINAL'), (""about\no'clock"", 'TIME'), ('minutes before midnight', 'TIME'), ('nearly eight', 'CARDINAL'), ('Montargis', 'LANGUAGE'), ('seventy miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('Irom Paris', 'PERSON'), ('Roanne', 'PERSON'), ('M. Deschanel', 'NORP'), ('2s miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('chen', 'PERSON'), ('Walking Along Track', 'PERSON'), ('M. Deschanel', 'PERSON'), ('more than a mile', 'QUANTITY'), ('Iatin', 'PERSON'), ('darkt8', 'ORG'), ('M. Desdnel', 'PERSON'), ('PresiMol', 'ORG'), ('ihc', 'PERSON'), (""Lorcy 1'"", 'ORG'), ('Lorcy', 'PERSON'), ('aore than seven miles', 'QUANTITY'), ('ten', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('M. Deschanel', 'PERSON'), ('J0', 'PRODUCT'), ('vou', 'ORG'), ('J. Paul Deschanel', 'PERSON'), ('Refallie,1', 'NORP'), ('vou', 'ORG'), ('Tou', 'PERSON'), ('Madam', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('M. Pauf', 'PERSON'), ('Sbut', 'ORG'), ('Thut', 'PERSON'), ('State', 'ORG'), ('ho', 'PERSON')]"
57,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t514168_article_67,article,1919-02-24,"(SPECIAL TELEGRAM TO THE HERALD.)
Lospor. Sunday. — Mrs. Wheeldon,
Who was the central 6gure in the case of
the plot to poison Mr. Lloyd George and
Mr. Arthur Henderson in 1917; died gesterday from influenza
The story of the conspiracy was tho
sensation of the vear. Also accused in
connection with the plot were Mrs.
Wheeldon’s, daughters and her son-inlaw, Alfred George Mason, a Southampton chemist.
Mrs. Wheeldon was sent to- Holloway
Prison, then to Aylesbury, where she began hunger-striking. The Masons were
released, on the Prime Minister's suggestion, a few weeks ago. Mrs. Wheeldon was fifty-six years. of age.","[('HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Lospor', 'ORG'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('Wheeldon', 'PERSON'), ('Lloyd George', 'PERSON'), ('Arthur Henderson', 'PERSON'), ('1917', 'DATE'), ('Wheeldon', 'PERSON'), ('Alfred George Mason', 'PERSON'), ('Southampton', 'GPE'), ('Wheeldon', 'PERSON'), ('Holloway\nPrison', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('Aylesbury', 'GPE'), ('a few weeks ago', 'DATE'), ('Wheeldon', 'PERSON'), ('fifty-six years', 'DATE')]"
58,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51395x_article_143,article,1919-02-03,"To rur Epriog or THE HEnALD:—
Would gou kindly inform me, tbrough
vour paper, if Marg Pickford, the
morie actress, died nhen gou had 1t
published in geur paper that she was
dring with the flu? Respectfully.
Sor W. S. Mnrens.
Co. I, 11th U.S. Marines
Gierres, France.","[('Marg Pickford', 'PERSON'), ('nhen gou', 'PERSON'), ('1', 'CARDINAL'), ('Sor W. S. Mnrens', 'PERSON'), ('11th', 'ORDINAL'), ('France', 'GPE')]"
59,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539382_article_31,article,1920-02-07,"Flu Decreases in Finland.
Umisiserons.—Influenza is decreas
ing. Cases last. weck totalled 542 instend ol 1,342 tho previous weck
To Discuss Turkish Problem.
Lorpos. — The preliminarg disenssion of the Turkish question mill take
place in London next weck. M. Millerand arrires on Wednesdas","[('Finland', 'GPE'), ('Umisiserons.—Influenza', 'ORG'), ('542', 'CARDINAL'), ('1,342', 'CARDINAL'), ('To Discuss Turkish Problem', 'ORG'), ('Lorpos', 'ORG'), ('Turkish', 'NORP'), ('London', 'GPE'), ('M. Millerand', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesdas', 'ORG')]"
60,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51405p_article_22,article,1919-02-13,"According to the figures published bythe Paris statistical service for the sixth
weck of the gear it would appear that the
death rate was somewhat on the increase
with a'total of 1,213 deaths, as compared
with 1,076, the average for the season.
Spanish.“flu'' is credited with ninety-one
victims, while other infectious diseases
only claimed ien. There were serent,dre deahs due to rolence, and six 70
suicide.
 ","[('Paris', 'GPE'), ('sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('1,213', 'CARDINAL'), ('1,076', 'CARDINAL'), ('the season', 'DATE'), ('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('ninety-one', 'CARDINAL'), ('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('70', 'CARDINAL')]"
61,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51405p_article_57,article,1919-02-13,"(SPECTAL TELESRAM 7O THID HERALD.)
Lornor, Wednesday. — Lady Broadbeut dieck from broncho-pneumouia; Following influenza, on Sunday last. Sho
was the daughter of Mr. John Harpin,
and-married Bir William-Heury Broadbent,tho eminont consulting physiclan,
in 1863. Hor husband died in 1907","[('THID', 'PERSON'), ('Lornor', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday', 'DATE'), ('Lady Broadbeut', 'PERSON'), ('Sunday', 'DATE'), ('John Harpin', 'PERSON'), ('Bir William-Heury Broadbent', 'PERSON'), ('1863', 'DATE'), ('1907', 'DATE')]"
62,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51405p_article_56,article,1919-02-13,"GSPECIAL TELEGRAM' TO THE HERALD.)
LonpoN, Weduesdty. — Mr. Gsorge.
Paülding, of the famous, railway building firm, died at Effingham, Surrey, on
Monday from heart failure, following influenza, at the age of. sixty-fóur. Mr
Paulding was a canstructional engineer
Of. world-wide reputé. One of. the laßt
préjects, with which, Mr.Paulding was
connested was the building of the Murman Räilyay, which, eztending. from
Pétragrad tothe ice-freé. port of Katharinadistanceappfgsimately öfI.
iniles—was.öf the greatest militarz välue
toRussia.","[('TELEGRAM', 'ORG'), ('Weduesdty', 'PERSON'), ('Gsorge', 'PERSON'), ('Effingham,', 'FAC'), ('Surrey', 'PERSON'), ('Monday', 'DATE'), ('the age of', 'DATE'), ('sixty', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Paulding', 'PERSON'), ('Räilyay', 'PERSON'), ('Pétragrad', 'GPE'), ('Katharinadistanceappfgsimately öfI.\niniles—was.öf', 'FAC')]"
63,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51420p_article_89,article,1919-02-28,"one's contempt for him as a diplomatist.
Another illusion has, béen shattered by
the prevailing outbreak of grippe. It was
formerly thought that influenza rarely,
vory rarely, attacked a person twice, not
because one attack was necessarily' sufficient. because fatal, but because it conferred a sortof immunity. This idea
has now been-proved erroneous. Accord-
ing to statistics gathered byrthe Matin.
about a third of those now suffering from
grippe have had a previous attack quite
recently. Instead of &cquiring immunity,
they would seem to have been rendered
more susceptible to the malady.
No precaution should be neglected,
therefore, to avoid possible contagion,
particularly in viem of the virulence of
the present epidemic. In England, the
deaths attributed to influenza numbered","[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Matin', 'PRODUCT'), ('about a third', 'CARDINAL'), ('England', 'GPE')]"
64,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51420p_article_197,article,1919-02-28,"epidemic, commonly known as Spanish
Flu, both in England and in France,
the Matin’' has been prompted to ask.
the opinion of Professor Albert- Robin
on the subject.
The“Matin' warus the public#tliat a
person is not immune because he has
already been a. victim to the disease. On
the contrary, experieuce has shown that
those who have already suffered are more
prone than others to another attack","[('Spanish', 'NORP'), ('England', 'GPE'), ('France', 'GPE'), ('Matin', 'PERSON'), ('Robin', 'PERSON'), ('The“Matin', 'ORG')]"
65,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t51420p_article_210,article,1919-02-28,"(SPECTAL, TELEGRAM TO TIIE HERALD.)
LospoN, Thursday.—It is believed that
next week will see the maximum deathroll of the present alarming epidemic of
influenza, as in the ordinary way the
height is reached after a-period of five
or six weeks have elapsed. Weather conditions, honever, are always liable to
influence this rule.
Of the 3,046 deaths reported in yesterday's telegram, many were those of persons over sixty-five.
Second Attack of“Flu“ Possible.
The recent damp weather having
brought about ar recrudescence of the","[('SPECTAL', 'ORG'), ('TELEGRAM TO TIIE HERALD', 'ORG'), ('Thursday.—It', 'GPE'), ('next week', 'DATE'), ('five', 'CARDINAL'), ('six weeks', 'DATE'), ('3,046', 'CARDINAL'), ('yesterday', 'DATE'), ('sixty-five', 'CARDINAL'), ('Second Attack', 'LOC')]"
66,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53189t_article_17,article,1918-07-19,"Wir# zun Barrisn AnMIEs.
Thursday.
The enemy's aggressiveness has been
confined this week to heary bursts of
artillery fire. His batteries have been
very energetic during the night around
Tpres and against the Allied trenches
defending the Flemish hills. His infantry, however, is apparently tod weak or
dispirited to give any exhibitions of hostility, and is content to hold the defences.
If the Fourth German Army tries
again to advance from Kemmel against
Vpres and the hills overlooking it, fresh
divisions will undoubtedly be sent
through these weary trench garrisons if
the latter are not relieved beforehand.
Some of the trench garrisons have been
depleted by influenza, and these men
who had been sent to medical camps are
only just beginning to return in any
number.
In spite of the severe cannonade of
the Fourth and Sixth German Armies.
north of La Bassée, a rast amount of
constructional work has been carried out
behind their front, which embraras al
the Flanders defences.","[('# zun', 'MONEY'), ('Thursday', 'DATE'), ('this week', 'DATE'), ('Tpres', 'ORG'), ('Allied', 'ORG'), ('Flemish', 'NORP'), ('the Fourth German Army', 'ORG'), ('Kemmel', 'GPE'), ('Vpres', 'PERSON'), ('Fourth', 'ORDINAL'), ('Sixth', 'ORDINAL'), ('La Bassée', 'ORG'), ('embraras al', 'PERSON'), ('Flanders', 'ORG')]"
67,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53189t_article_130,article,1918-07-19,"(FROM THE HERALD'S CORRESPONDENT.)
Lorpos, Thursday.—The King’s decision that no alcchol should be consumed
at the Royal table or by the household
during the war is strictly adhered to in
every particular at Buckingham Palace.
One of the organizers of the recent
women's procession was seized with an
attack of influenza while in the quadrangle after the. ceremony. She was
taken into the Palace by an officer attached to the household, who, in sending
the servants fer water said,This is a
teetotal house, and we cannot get brandy
or any other stimulant for vou.'2","[('CORRESPONDENT', 'ORG'), ('Lorpos', 'ORG'), ('Royal', 'ORG'), ('Buckingham Palace', 'FAC'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Palace', 'ORG')]"
68,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t53189t_article_197,article,1918-07-19,"point I decline all responsibility.'
A delightful evening was passed at the
new quarters of the American Red Cross
Club for Women, 6 früe Chauveau-Lagarde, by those who braved'the beat and
storm of Wednesday night.
M. André Baugé's fine voice was heard
with effect in the prologue from Pagliacci, in the baritone solo from Le
Barbier de Séville,'' and as an encore in
a delicate chanson de Provence.
Major Dagincourt, who as surgeonmajor did much to suppress the epidemic
of typhus in Serbia, made an interesting and courteous address on the“Sentiments of France for America. His
allusions to what had been accomplished
by women during the war were particuarly appreciated, as also his tribute to
the Red Cross and especially to its
women workers.
Mlle. Suzanne Coulomb, of the Théätre Sarah Bernhardt, delighted thie audience by her presence and by the grace
with which she recited some of Lafontaine's fables and“La Brouette, by
Edmond Rostand.","[('Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('Club for Women', 'ORG'), ('6', 'CARDINAL'), ('Chauveau-Lagarde', 'PERSON'), ('Wednesday night', 'TIME'), (""M. André Baugé's"", 'PERSON'), ('Pagliacci', 'ORG'), ('Le\nBarbier de Séville', 'FAC'), ('chanson de Provence', 'ORG'), ('Dagincourt', 'PERSON'), ('Serbia', 'GPE'), ('America', 'GPE'), ('the Red Cross', 'ORG'), ('Mlle', 'PERSON'), ('Suzanne Coulomb', 'PERSON'), ('Sarah Bernhardt', 'PERSON'), ('Lafontaine', 'ORG'), ('Brouette', 'PERSON'), ('Edmond Rostand', 'GPE')]"
69,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539040_article_31,article,1920-01-04,"Misfortunes nerer comé singly, and
it is not surprising that with anticipations of a Paris flood should come
fears of a recurrence of the influenza
epidemic, which
caused such worldwide ravages in 1918. Happily, the
best opinion in the medical profession is rather reassuring on this point,
and goes to indicate that there is little reason forapprehension. Siich
cases as have niade their appearauce
in Paris during the last, few, days
prove to be 6f. a mild and comparatively harmless form of#the disease,
and not of the cpidemie varietz
Atithe Lariboisière: Hospital the
head physician ofreach ward is obligech
to declare erery case of influenza clearIy characterised as such coming under
his care. In the last three days only
two such cases have been notified
And these twro cases were not of the.
infectious variety
No Recurrence of. Epidemic.
At# sthe Public. Health Servicé
nothing, it is declared, is known of
n recrudescence of,the dread epidemie.
At the Bureau of. Municipal Statistics
it was found that grippe was Tecorded in only sefen cases as among
the causes of death in Paris during
therlast weck of December. These
figures are hardly portentous in view
of ine fact that in the first week of
January, 1919, there were 142 deatks
from-grippe., While it is wise to be
carelul, there is no reason for anxiety.
The viers and warnings expressed
during the last Sware“. are again
being giren. At the Pasteur Institute
a promjuent professor said: In itself
grippe is not serious. It only.becomes
so When followed br pulmonary compliçations that are likely to derélop
in its later stages.
The. prephylaxis, or preventive
treatment, is simple: Avoid-all promischous exposure liable. to increase
the virus wlich may hare found lodg
ment. The therapeutic of the disease
is more complicäted.
Ve need not-be surprised by the
frequeney of dases of grippe at this
time. They aredue simply to conditions of temperature. The infectious
agents are not external to us. The
bacteria die rapidly. And the best disinfection is pienty of fresh air and sun
licht. the ultra-red and ultra-violet
rays of hich aresincomparable sauftary agents.","[('Paris', 'GPE'), ('1918', 'DATE'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('6f', 'CARDINAL'), ('Atithe Lariboisière:', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the last three days', 'DATE'), ('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('No Recurrence of.', 'WORK_OF_ART'), ('the Bureau of.', 'ORG'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('December', 'DATE'), ('the first week of\nJanuary, 1919', 'DATE'), ('142', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Pasteur Institute', 'ORG')]"
70,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539040_article_43,article,1920-01-04,"But it is better to avoid grippe than
to have to treat it. It will be aroided
by abstaining from assemblies, such as
cincmas, „theätres and
other public
places; by pulverizing the nostrils
with oil containing 5 per cent. of
gomenol; by good hygiene, by abstaining from excess, of any kind, and,
ahore all, by avoiding contact with
people suffering from grippe
In short, there is eridently grippe
in Paris;; but until the present time it
is localised and has not an epidemic
character. It. is moring-in isolated
centresand it is very probable that
even if it. becomes extended a little,
we shall not 'sée the grippe of 1918-19,
which prevailed throughout the world
and madle so gréat a number of vietims.","[('5 per cent', 'MONEY'), ('Paris', 'GPE'), ('1918-19', 'DATE')]"
71,new_york_herald_12148-bd6t539040_article_45,article,1920-01-04,"Therumor is current that Paris is
fnced by a new epidemic of grippe.
In realliy, one cannot yet Speak of an
epidemic. The fact is that in the city
chere have been noted isolated centres
of a disease which has all the appearances of grippe; but those
ccntres are
separated by large spaces
in ihich the
discäse is not preralent.
And as these
centres have Gxisted for
aboüt threo
weeks, withoub becoming general,
There.are grounds forthe hope that
the discase will remain localised.
What are the fentures of these centres?
Thefirst cases which appeared preveuted the intestinal form of grippe.
Such cases are ordinarily very serious. They are accompanied by an
